[Music]
welcome back
to five dollar shake first video of 2021
now we've decided to go a little bit of
a different route with our videos so
probably you'd see some hopefully you
see some improved changes but
uh if they don't improve we might take
them out later who knows
so this first video is going to be how
to recreate some of the most popular
flavors of ice cream
out there first one we're going to do is
fish food
so fish food is actually my personal
favorite flavor
and it is a chocolate ice cream with
marshmallow swirl and there's some
caramel sauce and some little chocolate
fish in there as well
but we don't need all of that i mean
when you look at the ingredients on the
back
you've got water cream
[Music]
milk
just an endless list of ingredients
but what do we really need to make this
we need just a few things we need a good
chocolate ice cream
caramel sauce marshmallow cream
and then a little chocolate fish so
that's what we're gonna do
the chocolate fish we don't have
a little fish mold small enough so
what i did was use the smallest one we
have which is actually dinosaurs
and we made a fudgy chocolate mix
and you do that by taking your chocolate
put it in a bowl add
a tablespoon or so of water put it in
the microwave for 30 45 seconds
something like that keep an eye on it
and then when it's done you can stir it
all together and what you'll be left
with is a chocolate that doesn't go rock
hard in the freezer
you'll then take your silicone mold and
then just push it into those
molds nice and carefully and put them in
the fridge ready to go off
when they're hardened or as hard as
they're going to be take them out pop
them out of the mould and put them in a
little container
put that in the fridge aside and then
you can get on with making your
marshmallow cream
the marshmallow cream is actually a
meringue but don't let the word meringue
scape tool
it's a very it's a swiss meringue so
it's very easy to make so you put
the all the ingredients in a double
boiler so that's in a bowl over the top
of some simmering water
and you gently bring it up to up to heat
stirring it constantly
until the sugar dissolves and the creamy
tartar is fully incorporated into the
base
then once it's up to 71 degrees c you
take it off the heat
and you whisk it up with your hand mixer
or your stand mixer or whatever mix
you've got
and keep going until you've got a lovely
glossy smooth finish
just like that when you're ready and
finished with that you can cover it and
put it in
the fridge so the caramel sauce we've
decided not to make it
and i went out and have a look in the
shops and see what i can get and you can
get the
the dolce de leche stuff but it's got
quite strong flavor so
as england is back on lockdown i decided
to go out and buy
some of that it's a salted caramel sauce
but it's
really really nice so if you ever wonder
whether to use jude's
go for it it's good stuff and then
finally the ice cream so the base we've
made here is
an eggless base so a philly style ice
cream
and for that we've put all the
ingredients into a pan
and just gently heated it up now that we
do that for a couple of reasons one
it helps to break down the fat molecules
within the milk and the cream
and then after you've heated it up and
allow it to cool
those fat molecules get encased in the
protein from the milk and cream
which gives you a much creamier finish
so once you've mixed it all up
put it into a jar or a bowl or something
put it in your fridge
for at least four hours but 24 hours
ideally because
in theory it should give you a better
smoother result now 20 minutes
or just before doing this i've taken the
mix out of the fridge
i've given a really good whisk up and
added two tablespoons
of dried milk powder
what that will do is it will add some
non-fat based
solids to your ice cream which will make
it a lovely little creamy texture when
you eat it
essentially we're ready to take the mix
out the fridge and get churning
so i've taken the base out of the fridge
and you can see the little air bubbles
on top this is created
by the milk powder all you do is just
give it a stir
combine it all back up again and now
you're ready to
put this base into your
ice cream maker
[Music]
and turn that for anywhere between 25
and
35 minutes
so once your ice cream is churned this
took 35 minutes
it's now time to time it up now we've
decorated
our own tub as you can see by this
lovely beer this is my wife that's
decorated this
now as you may see it has dinosaur on
the side and that's because we as i said
we didn't have the
fish shapes so we used the little dinos
so what we're going to do is to start
load up this
tub so you need to take your
your ice cream first and then
put some straight in the bottom like so
and then obviously now part of this
recipe is the marshmallow
and the chocolate and the caramel so
what we're going to do is going to take
some of our
little chocolates and dot them in there
we're going to take some of our caramel
sauce
and this is quite a thick sauce
and then obviously you need some of your
marshmallow cream
then take another spoon and just gently
stir it around
make sure it's incorporated like so
and then go again
[Music]
again you don't want to stir all this
together you still want those layers to
be there when you actually
open the tub at the end so just do one
very small
little bit of ice cream on top
now the ingredients listed below will
make
about one and a third to one and a half
tubs this tub is a ben jerry's size tub
it's a 16
ounce tub or 500 pounds
actually i think 16 ounces about 470 odd
mil but in england
and there you have
your homemade ben
and jerry's fish food i'm gonna put this
in the freezer
for about four hours and then we'll get
back out and show you what it looks like
[Music]
and here we have the two final ice
creams
so obviously this one is they're both
straight out of the freezer
this is the original fish food
completely untouched
and this is our own version of it
completely untouched so i'm going to
take a scoop out of each
put it on this plate and compare the two
[Music]
so how do they taste i mean color wise
the ben and jerry's is just slightly
darker
than our homemade version but ours has
got a lot more of the actual
marshmallow uh the chocolate's really
nice
loads of caramel in this one you can't
ever see the cow obviously there's a
little bit there
but there's not a massive amount so how
does it taste
it's nice and creamy obviously the
chocolate
melts in your mouth a little bit you
don't get any caramel flavor come
through there at all
ours same consistency
lots of caramel loads of marshmallow
interestingly enough the chocolate
isn't as hard as it is in here so that
fudgy texture with the
when you melt the chocolate with water
actually creates a much nicer frozen
chocolate texture
but all in all absolute success
if you want to try this at home do per
pot
cost wise it works out about 2 pound 80
to make one of these
if you're going to buy the ingredients
buy enough to make four or five parts of
it
and then you're cruising you can make
four or five pots for the same amount as
about one and a half maybe two of these
max
so a big cost saving and
it tastes incredible so anyway i hope
you've enjoyed
this video how to make ben and jerry's
fish food we've got some more of these
coming up soon we're going to do a
haagen-dazs
belgian chocolate one as well so stay
tuned for that
don't forget to visit us on social media
i'll put the links
down below or bottom of the screen or
something like that
and we hope to see you next time thanks
for watching